# **ALINA NAZARYAN**

alina.nazaryan@gmail.com +1301 825-4668 <u>linkedin.com/alinanazaryan</u> Columbia, MD, USA

#### **PROFILE**

UI/UX designer with an interior design background. Specializes in creating visually pleasing and functional design solutions that prioritize the user experience. Offers a unique blend of creativity and analytical skills, with a keen eye for detail. Skilled in effectively communicating with diverse clients, understanding their unique needs and finding solutions to achieve optimal results.

### **UI/UX DESIGN PROJECTS**

### Skincare products online store | CareerFoundry

February 2023

Designed and developed an online store platform by providing user flow diagrams, wireframes, desktop design and mockups using Figma.

View project here

# Price comparison app for iOS & Android | CareerFoundry

December 2022 - January 2023

Built a versatile app for both iOS and Android platforms, utilizing a deep understanding of the key differences between the operating systems using Adobe XD.

View project here

# Location-based Recommendation Responsive Web App | CareerFoundry

August 2022 - October 2022

Applied a user-centered design process to create a responsive web app for location-based recommendations, conducting competitive analyses, user interviews, surveys, and A/B testing. Developed polished high-fidelity screens, mockups, and prototypes utilizing Adobe XD. View project here

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Freelance Interior Designer

October 2020 - August 2022

# **SMTH Design Studio - Interior Designer**

January 2017 - September 2019 Yerevan, Armenia

- Transformed various spaces into practical environments, enhancing the overall quality of life for individuals.
- Collaborated closely with clients, actively listened to their desires and needs, and translated their vision into personalized design concepts.
- Applied innovative design solutions to overcome challenges and delivered visually stunning and highly functional interiors.

#### UI/UX SKILLS

UI / Visual Design

User Research

**User Flows** 

Mockups

Wireframing

Prototyping

Style Guides

Iconography

Typographic Hierarchy

Responsive Design

**Usability Testing** 

#### **TOOLS**

Adobe XD

**Figma** 

Sketch

Photoshop

Illustrator

Visual Studio

GitHub

#### **EDUCATION**

# UI/UX Design immersion CareerFoundry

January 2022- February 2023

Intensive project-based online training program with a focus on practical skills and industryrelevant projects. Specialized in front-end development.

## National University of Architecture and Construction of Armenia

September 2014 - May 2018

Bachelor's degree in Design. Majored in Interior Design.